Email: softluster4753@gmail.com Mobile: +82-10-3023-6720

Summary

An all-round player with extensive experience in various fields, expert in web server back-end development, particularly in the billing domain. Also proficient as a web front-end developer using React. Recently completed a full-time master's degree in natural language processing, fully funded with preferential treatment from Samsung Electronics. Previously worked on bootloader and device driver development as a system engineer in the BSP team.

Programming Skills

- Languages: Java, SQL, Shell script, Terraform HCL, Javascript (+ JSX, Typescript), HTML/CSS, Python, C/C++
- Tools: Spring, Docker, SoapUI, MySQL, React, PyTorch, HuggingFace
- Others: RESTful API, HTTPS (+ mTLS), Oauth 2.0, OOP/OOAD/DDD, Clean coding, TDD, Agile development (XP & Scrum), PCI-DSS (3DS2), BSP (Device driver), Jira/Confluence, Git/SVN

EXPERIENCE

Staff Engineer

Billing full-stack development — Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.

Suwon, Korea

Nov 2016 - Present

- o Led CP portal redevelopment: Used React, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, JPA (2020 2022)
- Developed DSA agreement (2021)
- Developed subscription product change for active subscription (2021)
- Implemented 3DS2 respond to EU PSD2 law regulations (2020)
- Developed remote login to Samsung Smart TV using smartphone (2020)
- o Developed integration test framework: Used SoapUI, Groovy (2019)
- o Migrate buyer portal from monolithic to MSA: Used AWS ECS, Terraform HCL (2019)
- o Led buyer portal redevelopment: Used React, Spring Boot, JPA (2018)

SRL methodology development — Hanyang University

Seoul, Korea

Researcher

June 2022 - Feb 2024

• Analyze and develop efficient methodologies for learning high-quality sentence representations based on large-scale language models: Used PyTorch, HuggingFace

BSP development — Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.

Suwon, Korea

Engineer

Feb 2015 - Nov 2016

- Debug kernel panics.
- Port ramdump feature to Samsung Smart TV Kernel (2016)
 - Contributed kexec-tools utility (https://bit.ly/3yG44df)

EDUCATION

Hanyang University

Seoul, Korea

Master of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 4.06/4.5

Mar 2022 - Feb 2024

Hongik University

Seoul, Korea

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering; GPA: 3.5/4.5

Mar 2022 - Feb 2024

Publications

• Young Hyun Yoo, Kyumin Lee, Minjin Jeon, Jii Cha, Kangsan Kim, and Taeuk Kim, Comparison and Analysis of Unsupervised Contrastive Learning Approaches for Korean Sentence Representations, *The 34th Annual Conference on Human and Cognitive Language Technology* (HCLT 2022).

Additional information

• Languages: English (professional working proficiency), Korean (native)

(Last update: 22/Feb/2024)